Artur Rodzinski Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Artur Rodzinski Collection 1868-1989 (bulk 1932-1957)
ML31.R64
Rodzinski, Artur, 1892-1958
5,000 items 62 containers 30 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The Artur Rodzinski Collection focuses on Rodzinski’s professional work as a conductor and his personal life in the United States, Europe and Latin America. It covers Rodzinski’s performances (live, radio and sound recordings), schedules and biographical information. The collection also includes material related to Rodzinski’s wife Halina. The materials primarily consist of correspondence, annotated music, magazine articles, newspaper clippings, legal documents, programs and advertisements. Most of the collection is in English, with a significant amount of material in Polish.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990--Correspondence.; Diamond, David, 1915-2005--Correspondence.; Gould, Morton, 1913-1996.; Lieberson, Goddard, 1911-1977--Correspondence.; Rodzinski, Artur, 1892-1958--Correspondence.; Rodzinski, Artur, 1892-1958.; Rodzinski, Artur, 1892-1958.; Rodzinski, Halina--Correspondence.; Rodzinski, Halina.; Rodzinski, Halina.; Rodzinski, Halina. Our two lives.; Schuller, Gunther.
Organizations
Cleveland Orchestra.; Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra.; New York Philharmonic.; Teatr Wielki w Warszawie.; Teatro comunale di Firenze.
Subjects
Conductors (Music)--Correspondence.
Form/Genre
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Programs.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The collection was given to the Library of Congress on January 4, 1999 by Richard Rodzinski, Rodzinski’s son.
Transfers
Sound recordings have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division of the Library of Congress.
Access and Restrictions
The Artur Rodzinski Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Performing Arts Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Artur Rodzinski was born in Spalato, Dalmatia (now Croatia) to Hermana Jozefa Rodzinski and Jadwiga Wiszniewski Rodzinska on January 2, 1892. Hermana, a Polish surgeon in the Austrian Army, was transferred to Lvov (formerly Lemberg and Lwów), Poland around 1897. Rodzinski's mother, Jadwiga, was a musician. At age 6, Rodzinski learned to play the piano and at age 15 was a page-turner during concerts in Lvov. In 1917, he served in the Austrian Army on the Russian front until he was wounded. After serving in the military, he married Ilse Reimesch, a German pianist. Rodzinski earned a law degree at the University of Vienna and took advanced musical classes at the Vienna Musical Academy with Joseph Marx and Franz Schreker in composition; Franz Schalk in conducting; and Emil von Sauer in piano. Returning to Lvov, he continued his music lessons with Jerzy Lalewicz. In 1918, Ilse gave birth to a son, Witold Rodzinski. To support his family, Rodzinski played the piano in a cabaret run by Marek Windheim and later as a piano accompanist for visiting singers and instrumentalists.
Rodzinski began as a choral conductor before making his debut as an orchestra conductor in 1920 at the Lwów Opera with Ernani. In 1921, he was employed with the Philharmonic in Warsaw (Filharmonia Narodowa) and became the first conductor of the Warsaw Opera (Teatr Wielki w Warszawie ). In the ensuing years, Rodzinski introduced Strauss’s Der Rosenkavalier, Wolf-Ferrari’s I gioielli della madonna, and Ravel’s L’heure espagnole.
In November1925, Leopold Stokowski invited Rodzinski to visit Philadelphia, where he made his debut as a conductor in the United States with the Philadelphia Orchestra on November 15, 1925. In 1926, Rodzinski was a guest conductor of the Philadelphia Orchestra and was later appointed assistant conductor with a signed contract through Concert Management Arthur Judson. Rodzinski made his debut in New York with the Philadelphia Orchestra conducting the premiere of a Miaskovski symphony. During the following three years in Philadelphia, he was in charge of the opera and orchestral departments of the Curtis Institute of Music, where Ilse taught piano.
Rodzenski left Philadelphia to become the director of the Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra in 1929. During the next three years in California, he guest conducted the Hollywood Bowl, the Young People’s Concert Series, the San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, the Philadelphia Orchestra, and the Cleveland Orchestra. In 1933, Rodzinski became a United States citizen.
In September 1933, Rodzinski became the conductor of the Cleveland Orchestra for the next ten years. Under Rodzinski, the Cleveland Orchestra became a leading virtuoso ensemble as he directed important performances such as the American premiere of Shostakovich’s Lady Macbeth of the Mzensk District on June 31, 1935. Additionally, he conducted the Cleveland Orchestra for Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS) national broadcasts and for Columbia Records sound recordings from 1939-42. During Rodzinski’s summer breaks, he often stayed at White Goat Farm in Stockbridge, Massachusetts, farming and raising goats. He would later sell his goats around 1941 to raise bees. In addition, during his breaks, Rodzinski worked as a guest conductor for the New York Philharmonic Orchestra in 1934 and 1937. Other guest conductor positions between 1936-38 included the Salzburg Festival, Chicago’s Ravinia Festival, appearances in Budapest, Paris, Salzburg, Vienna, and at Los Angeles’s Hollywood Bowl. He was the first American conductor to lead the Vienna Philharmonic. In 1937, upon Arturo Toscanni’s request, Rodzinski assembled and trained the National Broadcast Corporation’s (NBC) new symphony orchestra.
In 1934, Rodzinski divorced Ilse and married Halina Lilpop Wieniawsk in Warsaw, Poland, on July 19th. In 1936, he was decorated with the Polonia Restituta by Count Potocki. He was awarded, in 1938, an honorary music degree from Oberlin College and a Diplôme d’Honneur in France for his program of Polish music at the Paris International Exposition. In 1940, the Polish Relief Concert requested Rodzinski’s services, which resulted in a free concert to support the war around 1942.
In December 1942, Rodzinski signed a contract to be the music director of the New York Philharmonic. He appointed Leonard Bernstein as his assistant conductor the following year. Rodzinski conducted broadcasts for CBS with the New York Philharmonic from 1944-46. On January 23, 1945, Halina gave birth to Rodzinski’s second son, Richard (Riki). In 1946, Rodzinski sold White Goat Farm to Arthur Percival and bought an old golf course in Lake Placid, New York. Renaming Chubb Hill to Riki Hill, after his son, he started building a house. After difficulties in the terms of renewing his contract, he resigned from the New York Philharmonic in February 1947.
Rodzinski spent the next eleven months as the conductor of the Chicago Symphony Orchestra and opened their season at the Ravinia Festival on October, 7, 1947. In 1947, the film “Carnegie Hall,” was released. Rodzinski made a cameo appearance. In 1948, he directed Tristan, starring Kirsten Flagstad in her first concert in the United States after the war. Conflicts with the Chicago Symphony Orchestra’s management would end Rodzinski last permanent position as a conductor.
After leaving Chicago, Rodzinski, often traveling with his family, served as a guest conductor in the United States, Latin America and Europe. In November 1948, Rodzinski suffered his first heart attack in London, which canceled his schedule until the winter of 1949. He gave a performance in Los Angeles before conducting the 1949-50 season of the Havana Symphony Orchestra. During mid-season break, he conducted at a spring festival in San Francisco’s War Memorial Opera House. The Havana Symphony Orchestra management asked Rodzinski to be their permanent conductor, but when the musicians disbanded, the conductor was without an orchestra. His next engagements, managed by Sociedad Musical Daniel, were in Argentina at the Teatro Colon, Uruguay and Brazil.
Sociedad Musical Daniel, using their European contact Felicitas Keller, arranged work for Rodzinski in Europe. In 1951, he debuted at the Teatro alla Scala in Milan, followed by concerts in Venice, Naples, Los Angeles and Panama. In January and February 1952, Rodzinski performed at the Teatro Comunale di Firenze. Later that year, he started recording for Radio Audizioni Italia (R.A.I.) broadcasts, which continued through 1958. Additionally, Rodzinski conducted at the Teatro Comunale di Firenze during the 1952 Maggio Musicale Fiorentino. In September, Rodzinski performed at the Biennale di Venezia. He returned to New York to record with Remington Records for several weeks before returning to Florence, where he suffered an internal hemorrhage. Rodzinski recovered to conduct Prokofiev’s War and Peace at the 1953 Maggio Musicale Fiorentino, which was the first time the opera was performed outside of Russia. After spending the summer in Lake Placid, he returned in September 1953 for a three month engagement in Naples at the Teatro San Carlo. During that time, Rodzinski also performed Wagner’s Tannhäuser in Florence. Programs followed in Brussels, Milan, Torino, and Rome.
In 1954, Rodzinski conducted the Vienna Symphony Orchestra for the Westminster Recording Company. Additionally, he performed with the Accademia di Santa Cecilia Orchestra, on Radio Italiana di Roma broadcasts and at Teatro alla Scala. In September 1954, and again in 1956, Rodzinski recorded in London with Westminster. Upon his return to Italy, chest pains caused him to cancel his engagements until December 25, 1954. He then conducted the Accademia di Santa Cecilia Orchestra at the Teatro Argentina, but had to cancel the second program due to bronchitis. He recovered to perform in Florence, Rome, Torino, and with the R.A.I. ensemble.
During 1955-57, Rodzinski spent many hours performing on R.A.I. broadcasts between other concerts and resting. He conducted Tristan at the 1957 Maggio Musicale Fiorentino. During September 1957, Rodzinski recorded with Electrical and Musical Industries, Ltd. (EMI) in London, but he then fell into a brief coma, an illness that caused him to reschedule the completion of the work. In April 12, 1958, Rodzinski conducted the annual concert for Pope Pius XII at the Vatican, sponsored by R.A.I. Rodzinski returned to the United States in September 1958. On November 10, 1958, Rodzinski gave his last performance of Tristan at the Chicago Lyric Opera. Just seventeen days later, on November 27, 1958, Rodzinski died of heart failure in Boston, Massachusetts.
Scope and Content Note
The Artur Rodzinski Collection focuses on Rodzinski’s professional work as a conductor and his personal life in the United States, Europe and Latin America. The collection covers Rodzinski’s performances (live, radio and sound recordings), schedules, and biographical information. The materials primarily consist of correspondence, annotated music, magazine articles, newspaper clippings, legal documents, programs and advertisements. Other items include: photographs, notes, an address book, announcements, bills, brochures, catalogs and schedules. Most of the collection is in English, with a significant amount of material in Polish. Other languages include: Italian, Russian, German, French, Spanish, Hebrew and Japanese. A portion of the collection comes from Rodzinski’s wife, Halina, including items relating to her book, personal correspondence and articles published after the conductor’s death. Printed music that was not annotated was removed from the collection and is cataloged separately in the Library of Congress Music Division’s general collections.
Organization of the Artur Rodzinski Collection
The Artur Rodzinski Collection is organized into six series:
Correspondence
Annotated Music
Scrapbooks
Subject Files
Legal Documents
Miscellaneous
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006577403
Container List
- Correspondence, 1931-1976, bulk 1938-1953 (Box 1-11)
  This series contains letters, telegrams, invitations, and postcards. Some letters include contracts, schedules, programs, bills, royalty statements, business cards, brochures, photographs, advertisements, newspaper clippings and magazine articles. The correspondence documents Rodzinski’s professional life, such as the scheduling of guest conductor positions, programs and publicity; reviewing and finding scores; signing contracts; and responding to requests from composers, conductors, other performers and fans. The materials cover performances in the United States, Latin America and Europe. There is personal correspondence, including salutations from friends. Some of the major correspondents are Ada Finzi, Goddard Lieberson, and Ernesto de Quesada. Rodzinski’s outgoing correspondence was often written and/or typed by his wife, Halina, or one of his secretaries. Some of the correspondence is addressed to Halina, instead of Artur, and includes information requested for her book, Our Two Lives. While the majority of the series is in English, a significant amount is in Polish with smaller amounts in Italian, German, Russian, French and Spanish.
  The series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - A.F. of M. see American Federation of Musicians. Local 802
  - A.I. Root Company, 1942 (Box 1/1)
  - Abram, Jacques, n.d. (Box 1/2)
  - Accademia di Santa Cecilia, 1952-1953 see also Porrino, Ennio (Box 1/3)
  - Accademia Nazionale di Santa Cecilia see Accademia di Santa Cecilia
  - Achron, Lindon, 1942 see also Alexander, Josef (Box 1/4)
  - Acro Associates, Inc., 1950 (Box 1/5)
  - Adams, Jack see Jack Adams and Co.
  - Adams, Robert see Jack Adams and Co.
  - Adler, Clarence, 1951 (Box 1/6)
  - Adler, Frederick Charles, 1945 (Box 1/7)
  - Adler, Hans see Konzert-Direktion Hans Adler
  - Adler, Max, 1949 (Box 1/8)
  - Adomián, Lan, 1945 (Box 1/9)
  - Advise & Regis, 1952 (Box 1/10)
  - Agenzia Internazionale Concerti, 1949-1950 (Box 1/11)
  - Agenzia Lirica Concertistica Internazionale, 1950-1953 see also Finzi, Ada (Box 1/12)
  - Ahrendt, Karl, 1948 see also Alexander, Josef (Box 1/13)
  - Ainsley, W.M., 1944 (Box 1/14)
  - Akon, Alfred, 1945 (Box 1/15)
  - Akron Beacon Journal, 1942 (Box 1/16)
  - Albert B. Ashforth, Inc., 1949-1951 (Box 1/17)
  - Alberto, Pisani, 1953 (Box 1/18)
  - Albi Manufacturing Company, Inc., 1953 (Box 1/19)
  - ALCI see Agenzia Lirica Concertistica Internazionale
  - Alcotea see Agenzia Lirica Concertistica Internazionale
  - Alexander, Josef, 1942-1947 (Box 1/20)
  - Alexeeva, Mrs. see Soviet Union. Posol’stvo (U.S.)
  - Allen, George Venable see United States. Embassy (Yugoslavia)
  - Allen, Kenneth L., Jr. see Kenneth Allen Associates, Inc.
  - Allen, Larry see Music Corporation of America
  - Am-Rus Music Corporation, 1942 (Box 1/21)
  - American-Canadian Concerts and Artists see Kachouk, Michel
  - American Federation of Musicians. Local 802, 1949-1950 (Box 1/22)
  - American Music Center (New York, N.Y.), 1948 (Box 1/23)
  - Amkniga Corporation, 1934 (Box 1/24)
  - Anders, Marieo L., 1942 (Box 1/25)
  - Anderson, Lois see Anderson, Oliver William
  - Anderson, Oliver William, 1949 (Box 1/26)
  - Anello, John see Milwaukee County (Wis.). Park Commission
  - Angelicum dei Frati Minori, 1953 (Box 1/27)
  - Antell, Eleanor see National Concert and Artists Corporation
  - Antheil, George, 1943-1950 (Box 1/28)
  - Antonini, Alfredo, 1947 (Box 1/29)
  - Antrim, Thomas M. see Liberty Mutual Insurance Company
  - Argentina. Consulado General (New York, N.Y.), 1950 (Box 1/30)
  - Armed Forces Master Records, Inc., 1942 (Box 1/31)
  - Armitage, Merle see Cowles Magazines, Inc. see Simon and Schuster, Inc.
  - Armsby, Leonora Wood, 1945-1950 (Box 1/32)
  - Arneill, James Rae, 1949 (Box 1/33)
  - Arnell, Richard, 1945 (Box 1/34)
  - Arnold, Alfred see Arnold Motorcycle Company
  - Arnold Motorcycle Company, 1942 (Box 1/35)
  - Arnovick, Peter Gerald, n.d. (Box 1/36)
  - Arnstein, Karl see Goodyear Aircraft Corporation
  - Arpesani see Teatro alla Scala
  - Arrowhead Music Camp, 1948 (Box 1/37)
  - Art of Musical Russia Co., n.d. (Box 1/38)
  - Arthur, Nela, 1937 (Box 1/39)
  - Ashe, B.F., 1949 (Box 1/40)
  - Aspuru, Manuel, 1950 (Box 1/41)
  - Associated Music Publishers, 1942-1953 (Box 1/42)
  - Associated Musicians of Greater New York see American Federation of Musicians. Local 802
  - Associated Negro Press, 1944 (Box 1/43)
  - Aszkenazy, n.d. (Box 1/44)
  - Automobile club d’italia, 1952 (Box 1/45)
  - Autori, Franco, 1943-1945 (Box 1/46)
  - Avshalamoff, A., 1950-1951 (Box 1/47)
  - Babin, Vitya Vronsky, n.d. (Box 1/48)
  - Bacevičius, Vytautas, 1944 (Box 1/49)
  - Bacon, Ernst, 1945 (Box 1/50)
  - Bacon, Jacqueline see Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra
  - Baker, Sidney, 1950 (Box 1/51)
  - Baker, W.D. see Farmers and Merchants National Bank of Los Angeles
  - Ball, Mary see National Concert and Artists Corporation
  - Baltimore Symphony Orchestra see Stewart, Reginald
  - Bank of England, 1948-1949 (Box 1/52)
  - Barber, Samuel, 1936-1945 (Box 1/53)
  - Barera, Orlando, n.d. (Box 1/54)
  - Barkentin, Marjorie, 1934-1935 (Box 1/55)
  - Barrett, Edward Ware, 1951 (Box 1/56)
  - Barrett, Ethel see Gingold, Josef
  - Barrett, Herbert, 1942-1945 (Box 1/57)
  - Barrett, Jim see Gingold, Josef
  - Barrie, George N., 1944 (Box 1/58)
  - Barron, Rick & Rockmore, 1942-1949 (Box 1/59)
  - Barry, Roberto F. see Boosey & Hawkes Inc.
  - Barwig, Norbert J., 1950 (Box 1/60)
  - Barzin, Leonee see National Orchestral Association (U.S.)
  - Basham, Lenard, 1945 (Box 1/61)
  - Bass, William see Columbia Records, Inc.
  - Bate, Stanley, 1942-1945 (Box 1/62)
  - Bauer, Karl F. see Associated Music Publishers
  - Baume, Emile, 1944-1945 (Box 1/63)
  - Bay Cities Music Association, 1929 (Box 1/64)
  - Bazykin, V. see Soviet Union. Posol’stvo (U.S.)
  - Bean, Betty Randolph see Boosey & Hawkes Inc. see San Francisco (Calif.). Art Commission
  - Bechert, Paul, 1949 (Box 1/65)
  - Becker, John J., 1947-1948 (Box 1/66)
  - Beek, Johanna see Nederlandsche Concertdirectie
  - Behrens, Edith see Columbia Records, Inc.
  - Béique, Pierre see Concerts Symphoniques de Montréal
  - Benardi, Mr. see Agenzia Lirica Concertistica Internazionale
  - Bennet, Robert Russell, 1943 (Box 1/67)
  - Berenbau, 1950 (Box 1/68)
  - Berezowsky, Nicolai, 1942-1943 (Box 1/69)
  - Berg, Daniel George, 1945 (Box 1/70)
  - Bergamini, Herbert M., 1950 (Box 1/71)
  - Bergen Evening Record, 1943 (Box 1/72)
  - Berkshire Music Center, 1942 (Box 1/73)
  - Bernard R. La Berge, Inc. see Boosey & Hawkes Inc.
  - Bernhardt, Sarah see Beu
  - Bernstein, Leonard see Bergen Evening Record see Pelletier, Wilfrid
  - Best, Allen see Universal Recording Co. Inc.
  - Beu, 1951 (Box 1/74)
  - Beu, Sidney, 1937 (Box 1/75)
  - BHB see Boosey, Hawkes, Belwin Inc.
  - Biennale di Venezia, 1952 (Box 1/76)
  - Biétry-Salinger, Jehanne, 1950 (Box 1/77)
  - Biggs, Edward Power, 1943-1944 (Box 1/78, 13/1)
  - Binder, Abraham Wolf, 1945 (Box 1/79)
  - Bird, Remsen D. see Hollywood Bowl Association
  - Bishop, Warden see Willy-Overland Motors
  - Blackwell, Ellen Lee, 1942 (Box 1/80)
  - Blair, Floyd G., 1949 (Box 1/81)
  - Bliss, Arthur, Sir, n.d. (Box 1/82)
  - Bloch, Ernest, 1944-1945 (Box 1/83)
  - Block, Frederick, 1942-1943 (Box 1/84)
  - Bloomfield, Fowerbaugh and Ray, 1948-1949 (Box 1/85)
  - Bloomfield, Kitty E., 1949 (Box 1/86)
  - Bloomfield, Louis A. see Bloomfield, Fowerbaugh and Ray
  - Bloomfield, Theodor, 1943-1948 (Box 1/87)
  - Blossom, Betty, n.d. (Box 1/88)
  - Boas, Ernst Philip, 1949 (Box 1/89)
  - Bodenstein, Meyer see Barron, Rick & Rockmore
  - Bogen, Samuel A. see Davies, Charles
  - Bolet, [Jorge], 1951 (Box 1/90)
  - Bolin, Luis A. see Spanish State Tourist Department
  - Bonetti, Jose Alberto see Teatro Colón (Buenos Aires, Argentina)
  - Bonisconti, Angiolamaria see Radio audizioni Italia
  - Bonsetetten, Betty, 1949 (Box 1/91)
  - Boosey & Hawkes Inc., 1942-1951 (Box 1/92, 61/1)
  - Boosey, Hawkes, Belwin Inc., 1944 (Box 1/93)
  - Bornschein, Franz Carl, 1942 (Box 1/94)
  - Borós, Paul, n.d. (Box 1/95)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1936-1950 (Box 1/96)
  - Bouchonnet, N.D. see Office Artistique Continental
  - Bowles, Paul, 1945 (Box 1/97)
  - Bowles, Peter, 1945 (Box 1/98)
  - Boyd, Margaret R. see Stadium Concerts, Inc.
  - Bradford, Lindsay see New York Committee of the National War Fund
  - Brailowsky, Alexander, 1944-1952 (Box 1/99)
  - Brailowsky, Ela see Brailowsky, Alexander; see Brailovsky, Sacha
  - Brailowsky, Sacha, 1947-1953 see also Brailowsky, Alexander (Box 1/100)
  - Brainina, Balbina see Simkhovitch, Mary Kingsbury
  - Brant, Henry, 1948 (Box 1/101)
  - Braunstein, Josef, 1942 (Box 1/102)
  - Breitenfeld, Frederick see Davies, Charles
  - Briggs, Mrs. Robert, 1944 (Box 1/103)
  - Brill, Belle G., 1943 (Box 2/1)
  - British Consulate Central, New York, 1940 (Box 2/2)
  - Broadcasting Corporation of Japan see Nihon Hōsō Kyōkai
  - Broder, Nathan see G. Schirmer, Inc.
  - Brott, Alexander, 1945 (Box 2/3)
  - Broude Brothers Limited, 1950 (Box 2/4)
  - Brown, Lolita see Time, Inc.
  - Brown, Royal, 1976 (Box 2/5)
  - Browne, Kenneth H., 1949 (Box 2/6)
  - Brun, Marie G. see Chateau Elysée
  - Brundage, Story and Rose, 1942-1953 (Box 2/7)
  - Buchkniga, 1934 (Box 2/8)
  - Buchman, Frank, 1942 (Box 2/9)
  - Bucholz, R.J., 1942 (Box 2/10)
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie, 1943 (Box 2/11)
  - Burns, T.J. see Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States
  - Buryin, Richard, 1943 (Box 2/12)
  - Busch, Frieda, 1939-1940 (Box 2/13)
  - Bustini, Alessandro see Accademia di Santa Cecilia
  - Byman, Barnett see National Orchestral Association (U.S.)
  - Byrns, Harold, 1942-47 (Box 2/14)
  - B miscellaneous, 1942 (Box 2/15)
  - Cabot, Hugh see Russian War Relief, Inc.
  - CAC see Canadian Concerts and Artists
  - Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1943-1944 (Box 2/16, 13/2)
  - Cadman Choral Club of Santa Ana, Calif., 1933 (Box 2/17)
  - Caillet-Bois, Horacio see Teatro Colón (Buenos Aires, Argentina)
  - Caldwell, William A. see Bergen Evening Record
  - Calvin, I.B., 1942 see also Cleveland Orchestra (Box 2/18)
  - Camilla, 1953 (Box 2/19)
  - Campese, Gino, 1950 (Box 2/20)
  - Canadian Concerts and Artists, 1945 (Box 2/21, 61/2)
  - Carisch, 1950-1953 (Box 2/22)
  - Carissimo, 1951 (Box 2/23)
  - Carl, n.d. (Box 2/24)
  - Carl Fischer Inc., 1945 (Box 2/25)
  - Carnegie Hall Recording Co., 1951 (Box 2/26)
  - Carpenter, Allan see Wolf & Davis
  - Carpenter, Ellen see Carpenter, John Alden
  - Carpenter, John Alden, 1935-1950 (Box 2/27)
  - Carson Ruff, Margaret see Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.)
  - Carter, 1943 (Box 2/28)
  - Carter, Edward Clark see Russian War Relief, Inc.
  - Carvalho, Eleazar de, 1946-1951 see also Sociedad Musical Daniel (Box 2/29)
  - Casadesus, Robert, 1944 (Box 2/30)
  - Casillo, Irene see Agenzia Internazionale Concerti
  - Cassidy, Claudia, 1948-1951 (Box 2/31, 60/1)
  - CBS see Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.
  - Celentano, Rosario, 1942 (Box 2/32)
  - Centropa Concert Organisation, 1948-1953 (Box 2/33)
  - Cesar Cianfoni, D. see Cianfoni, D. Cesar
  - Chajes, Julius, 1944 (Box 2/34)
  - Chapin, Katherine Garrison, n.d. (Box 2/35)
  - Chappell and Co. see Heilner, Irwin
  - Charles Foley, 1942 (Box 2/36)